Welcome into Jags AM. Brian Sexton
[music] along with John Oehser here on a
Tuesday morning and we're changing
things up a little bit. Not just a
different host today, but we're starting
with the head coach of the Jaguars, Liam
Cohen, who joins us from the NFL's
owners meetings in Phoenix, Arizona. The
owners [music] meetings began on Sunday
evening. There's lots to talk about and
of course we'll get to those things, but
first we bring in the head coach. Coach,
how are you?
Great, Brian. Appreciate it, man. Thanks
for having me on. Thank you for making
time for us this morning. Hey, just
generally, how's the pace of your second
off season? Or actually, your first off
season, your second spring with the
Jaguars. How different is it for you
this year than it was last year when you
put your feet on the ground?
Yeah, it's a lot different, I'll say. Um
this is probably the the first off
season Ashley and I and the and the
family has had in in roughly 5 to 6
years. So, uh to have a little bit of a
schedule, a routine, some stability that
involves pouring into football when when
at the office and and with the coaching
staff, but also having an opportunity to
be a be a husband, be a father, um and
and be able to spend some time with the
family at nights is is definitely nice
to have, to have some consistency
throughout an off season without moving
and restarting and and picking up and
uh being a part from your family. Um
it's been great to have so far.
Coach, we talked a little bit earlier
this off season about
the whole idea of coming back and but
you would think that you have a longer
off season cuz you're here, but you
don't really look at it that way. You
look at it more like, "Hey, we're losing
a week or two because of the rules that
you can't get with these guys because
you're not a new coach anymore." Uh talk
about your pace of the off season, what
you're trying to get done.
Yeah, it's definitely um
you know, you feel
a little bit of a sense of of urgency. I
mean, there there's there's no question
in my mind that's been the challenge
to the coaching staff, to our our
department staffs uh at the building.
The message has been um and and when the
players get in in in here, the message
will be uh how do we improve? How do we
get better with less time together? Flat
out. Less time together as a staff, less
time together
um once the players get in here and and
and so our time on task, our
intentionality has to be uh better than
ever. And and that's the challenge that
I have for everybody and myself
included. So,
um that's something that you work
through and and the way that you
schedule out your off season program and
plan and uh the amount of repetition,
the amount of time on each drill and uh
where you're allocating your time. And
and and so those are all the things that
we've been looking at and uh certainly
excited to get these players back in the
building here soon so we can really
start football. You know, momentum never
carries over from one season to the
next. Though most observers, fans also,
kind of think, "Well, we were 13 and
four." How do you change that mindset?
Or do you have to? Do these guys
understand that the boulder's back at
the bottom of the mountain, time to push
again?
Yeah, there's there's nothing that we're
defending.
Uh we're attacking everything that we're
doing.
Um that's the mindset and mentality. We
we could
you know, theoretically, we could get
better uh as a football team and not win
13 games. Like that's something that we
have to be prepared for. We have to
understand
um because if we live in those results
of last year,
uh this ain't going to be a fun process
and we won't like what we see. I got to
believe that. So, everything that we
attack uh from this off season moving
forward as we go into uh this new uh
regular season here, it's all brand new.
I mean, yes, there's going to be some
uh ability to start uh at ground one or
two and and different levels of your
offense, defense, and special teams,
your systems, but there's going to be
new players, there's new coaches,
there's new relationships and
communication uh ways that we need to
operate. And so, if we attack it the
same way as last year and we just say,
"Well, we already made that
relationship. We already had that
connection." Well, that's going to be a
different connection on this team
because every team is different.
Coach, I know you spoke with our guy
Ryan O'Halloran at the Times-Union
yesterday.
I think my favorite thing that I heard
from that was you talking about not
letting the stink of winning overwhelm
the stink of something else. I I love
the way you put that. Uh
clearly that's important to you this off
season. It's it sort of ties into the
last question. Anything specific that
you're addressing along those lines and
that's your focus along those lines?
Well, yeah, I said that you know,
winning is a fantastic deodorant and
covers up what stinks about you. It
covers up what your blind spots are,
what your negatives, what your
um areas of improvement are. And if we
can attack those areas with humility,
with honesty,
uh with a relentless pursuit to improve
those areas, then
uh we'll still continue to work on the
areas in which we were good and and we
need to hone in on those things, but uh
look, we're always looking for better
balance on offense, right? I think the
running game for the first eight weeks
of the season really kind of carried us
offensively and allowed us to to win
some of those games and then uh the pass
game in the second half of the season
really allowed us to go offensively. And
so, we have to create a little bit more
balance there. Defensively, just
continuing to find that balance between
rushing coverage and and and being able
to play a little bit
uh couple of different coverages in the
back end, couple couple different front
structures or pressures that you're
looking at and and looking at
uh you know, adding in in player
acquisition throughout the draft and
free agency and trades. You're you're
looking all at all those things during
this time. So,
um and then special teams wise, we're
constantly
uh getting new rule proposals throughout
from the league. And so, how does that
affect your formations and your schemes
and your fundamentals that you're
coaching? So, uh it's a lot. I mean,
it's never like we're just walking
through a day kind of just going through
the motions hoping to go home. I mean,
that's not the atmosphere we we want to
be in and that's not uh how we're
operating.
We haven't talked to you since you uh
signed Chris Rodriguez. How does he help
specifically
in the running game? A different style
than uh Travis Etienne was, but uh I
know you like what he can bring in terms
of down and distance, situational
consistency, things along those lines.
Yeah, I think like losing a player like
TJ, a first round pick, the the the
ability in the run and the pass and and
some of the production, like that's
going to be hard to match for for
anybody, right? But what I always really
appreciated about C-Rod, you know, when
working with him in Kentucky and then
following his career over the last few
years has been his his, you know,
rushing yards over expected and his
yards after contact. I mean, I think
those are the two areas that you look at
where you say like,
"Did you get more or about what the play
was blocked for? And are are people
bouncing off of you? Do you know how to
make people miss?" Like how do you make
people miss? There's a lot of different
ways to do that. And how do you gain
yards? There's a lot of different ways
to skin that cat. And ultimately,
uh for me and for the for the type of
style of team we want to be, to be able
to punch you in the mouth and and get
those some of those hard yards, getting
a guy like Chris to to complement that
room as it stands at right now with
Etienne, Laquon, and DJ and
um you know, those guys. So, we're just
trying to continue to add good football
players in there. How about one final
thought, coach? The draft is 23 days
away, a little more than 3 weeks. You
have 11 picks,
uh four on night two of the draft, which
is first night for the Jags without a
first round pick. Plus, you you you have
that keeping your attention. You get
some guys back this year from the draft
class last year who really weren't able
to contribute because of injuries. Caleb
Johnson stands out. Uh the second half
of the season, you didn't have Travis
Etienne. Just a thought on getting some
of those guys back on the field in year
two for them.
Yeah, we're excited about some of the
second year players that uh
you know, whether they were able to
contribute last year or not. Um but
specifically, the the Caleb Johnsons,
right? Jaylen McLoud didn't didn't
wasn't able to play much. Uh
Getting Jack Kaiser a year better,
right? Getting
um Travis Etienne
and schedule and and the way that we
look at those things on offense. Wyatt
Myalms, you know, Jordan Manheim, a lot
of young players that are we're
continuing to see
uh hopeful ascension from that can come
and and either be contributors or
competitors
um for for playing time.
Three weeks for your players back, three
weeks to the draft. A lot coming up.
Coach, we really appreciate you making
some time on a busy Tuesday morning in
Arizona.
I appreciate it, guys. Thanks for having
me on. Have a great day. That's the head
coach of the Jaguars coming off a 13 and
four season. And as he famously has
said, trying to wipe off the stink of
wins and making sure his team is ready
to go out and play their best football
in the fall of 2026. When we come back,
a little normalcy for you. We have
[music] big things next on Jags AM.